# **Michael Burton**

Raleigh, NC 27603 (252) 648-1266 meburton@ncsu.edu MichaelEBurton.github.io

### **Summary**

Highly motivated individual with proven abilities working independently and collaborating in interdisciplinary teams to turn data into business insights while an intern at the Boeing Company. Experienced in public speaking while instructing small groups through leadership roles as an Eagle Scout.

## **Education**

#### North Carolina State University | Raleigh, NC

Master's of Statistics May 2020

GPA: 3.95

Bachelor of Science in Statistics with a Minor in Mathematics

May 2019

Major GPA: 3.78, Cumulative GPA: 3.64

Magna Cum Laude

### **Relevant Coursework:**

Regression Analysis, Statistical Methods I & II, Experimental Design, Mathematical Statistics I & II, Statistical Computing & Data Management, Intermediate SAS Programming, Applied Time Series Analysis, Applied Bayesian Analysis, Applied Multivariate and Longitudinal Data Analysis, Survey Sampling, Introduction to Statistical Learning, Matrix Theory

#### **Skills & Certifications**

Certified Advanced Programmer for SAS 9 • Python • R • SQL • Unix • Git • C++

# **Professional Experience**

#### Statistical Practice Consulting Course

Raleigh, NC

Statistical Consultant

Jan 2020-May 2020

- Effectively communicated with clients to understand the research problem of interest
- Analyzed experimental data on a novel colorimetric assay to recommend changes to current layout
- Read, wrangled, cleaned, and analyzed data in R

The Boeing Company Seattle, WA

Data Science and Analytics Intern

May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team in Product Development's, Advanced Materials & Fabrication Group
- Analyzed experimental data and built predictive models using R
- Presented on the importance of tidy data and experimental design

Hanesbrands Inc. Winston-Salem, NC

**Advanced Analytics Intern** 

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- Performed clustering analysis in SAS to identify informative profit segments of bra styles from 36 million data points
- Built statistical model to find optimal color mix for bra styles to grow sales and reduce excess inventory
- Reported progress in weekly staff meetings & presented results in final presentations to executive leadership
- Demonstrated ability to explain technical terminology, and methods in layman terms

### **Awards & Honors**

**Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout Award** 

Jun 2014

**American Statistical Association** 

Mar 2017 - Present

NCSU Student Chapter: President ('18-'19), Vice President ('17-'18)

**Mu Sigma Rho National Statistics Honor Society** 

Mar 2018